# **Putut Budiutomo**

South Tangerang, Indonesia 12330 | www.linkedin.com/in/putut-budiutomo-5514a420b | +62 87737415691 | putut.budiutomo@student.upj.ac.id

### **ABOUT ME**

I am an active student at Pembangunan Jaya university, Information Systems Study Program. I am currently in semester 6. I am very passionate about anything related to technology, especially to build or develop computerized systems. For that I like to learn programming and analyze systems. I really like both of these fields. From semester 2 I started learning programming like javacsript, php, golang and other technologies to build a website. Of course, at this time my expertise is building a website and also analyzing all the necessary system requirements.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

**Essentials!** 

(October 2022 - January 2023)

Corporate Social Responsibility

Promoting products, services associated content over social media, during a means that's in step with an
organization's complete and social media strategy.

# Pembangunan Jaya University

Assistant Lecturer Employee Class Programming Language Course

(February 2022 – May 2022)

- Assist lecturers in preparing learning materials
- Presenting learning materials
- Mentoring students during practicum.
- Assess and review the results of student assignments

Assistant Lecturer Database Systems Course

(February 2022 – May 2022)

• Assess and review the results of student assignments

Chief Executive of Information Systems Study Program Company Visit Activities

(10 May 2023)

- Responsible for planning and organizing company visits for Information Systems Study Program students
- Establish good cooperation with the company to ensure the visit runs smoothly
- Responsible for answering Student questions, ensuring proper participation, and coordinating travel details
- Responsible for ensuring company visits go well. This includes providing transportation, managing attendance, arranging visiting agendas, arranging presentations or discussion sessions with companies, and ensuring safety and comfort during visits

## **EDUCATION**

Pembangunan Jaya University Bachelors of Computer Science

(September 2020 - Present) 3.64/4.00

**Ruang Guru Backend Engineering** 

(June 2022 – December 2022)

- Implement the software development process by using a code editor: Visual Studio Code, terminal, version control, and basic networking.
- Build a foundation for frontend development by learning step by step how to build websites using HTML and CSS and publish on the internet through the Netlify platform.
- Backend programming uses the Golang programming language including understanding the basic data structure and algorithms that are commonly used in building applications
- Understanding and implementing advanced concepts including unit testing in Golang, implementing Golang I/O including HTTP Server and Client, and understanding the concept of Concurrency in Golang.
- Learn step by step about knowing and using Database together with Golang, starting from data modeling, ERM, SQL to using GORM and a little introduction to NoSQL.
- Learn to create web-based applications with Golang starting from the REST API, the MVC model, using the Postman tool and deploying to Fly.io.

#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

# Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Informasi - Universitas Pembangunan Jaya

Academic Division · Jul 2022 - Present

# Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Informasi - Universitas Pembangunan Jaya

Academic Division · Jul 2021 - Jun 2022

# **SKILLS**

Unified Modelling Language, Customer Needs Analysis, Business Process Improvement, SQL database, Organizational Leadership, Communication Skills, Creative Problem-Solving, Critical Thinking, Backend Developer, Web Development, System Analyst.